LEIGH B. BIENEN PAPERS (APAP312) 1872, 1935, 1951-2011, Undated
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material, 1979-2011, Undated; 2; 7
  - Utah Exoneration and Innocence Assistance Bill of 2008, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Neil Alan Weiner dedication, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Laura Weizeorick and Christopher Tansey, Summaries of Illinois Death Row Convictions since 2003, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Wrongful Conviction Compensation, 2010; Undated (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Alex Yastrow, Radelet Study notes, time period of Cases, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Attorney's Letter to Governor Quinn Advocating for Abolition, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Illinois Death Penalty Literature, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Illinois House Bill 1519, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Illinois legislation to reinstate the death penalty, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Illinois Senate Bill 2276, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Senator Jeff Schoenberg and Governor Pat Quinn correspondence, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Annotation of Capital Punishment Reform Provisions in Illinois, Undated (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Annotation of Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Provisions 1990- 1993, Undated (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Beck v. Alabama (1981) cite statistics, Undated (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Capital Jury Project - Juror Interview Instrument Phase II Part A, Undated (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Capital Jury Project - Juror Interview Instrument Phase II Part B, Undated (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Case Summaries, Undated (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Data Dictionary, Undated (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Homicide Data - Douglas Mills, Undated (Floppy-disk 2)
  - Illinois Senate Resolution on Ryan Moratorium, Undated (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - January 1, 2004 Report of the Cook County State's Attorney's Office regarding monies received under Capital Crime Litigation Trust Fund Act, Undated (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Marcia Lehr - election of states attorneys in Illinois, Undated (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - List of Aggravating Factors Associated with Illinois Death Row Inmates During Eligibility Phase, Undated (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Map of Illinois Counties, Undated (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Montana Cases (FN 135), Undated (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - "New chamber for execution ready to go into service" (Illinois), Undated (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Note to John Murphy of the Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology, Undated (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Prosecutorial discretion - case summaries, Undated (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Roots of Trial by Jury [class materials?], Undated (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Slides: Implementing (or Nullifying) Atkins v. Virginia by John Blume, Sheri Johnson and Chris Seeds, Undated (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Table of Illinois Court of Claims cases, Undated (Box 7, Folder 78)
- Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee Records, 2003-2010; 3; 0.8
  Series contains records from Leigh Bienen's membership in the Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee. Material includes correspondence, meeting minutes, notes, and drafts and final copies of published reports.
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Act, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - John Cullerton, Kirk Dilliard, and Peter G. Baroni, "Capital Punishment Reform in Illinois: A Model for the Nation", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Appointments, meetings, hearings, and Annual Reports, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee Public Hearing - Springfield, 2006 November 13 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Peter G. Baroni, Special Counsel - Summary of Capital Cases Decided by the Illinois Supreme Court January 2003 to February 2007 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Material - Survey methods, data, meeting minutes, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lobbying Entry Registration, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Public Hearing - Chicago, 2007 February 26 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Capital Crime Tables, 2008; 2009 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - David E. Olson presentation slides with notes, ca. 2008 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - David E. Olson, "Trends in the Number & Characteristic of Prison Sentences Imposed on Those Convicted of First Degree Murder in Illinois", (presented to the Illinois Capital Reform Study Committee), ca. 2008 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Slides of Graphs from meeting, 2008 January 28 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Act with Police Investigation Subcommittee, 2009; 2010 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hearing of the Capital Reform Study Committee, 2009 March 2 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee Fifth Annual Report, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2009 December 17 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - David E. Olson, et. al., "Experiences with the Implementation of Homicide Investigative Reforms: A Survey of Illinois Local Law Enforcement Agencies", (Draft) Prepared for the Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee, 2009 July (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - David E. Olson, et. al., Final Report - The Impact of Illinois' Truth-in-Sentencing Law on Sentence Lengths, Time to Serve and Disciplinary Incidents of Convicted Murderers and Sex Offenders, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - David E. Olson, et. al., "Tables Summarizing the Sentencing of First Degree Murderers in Illinois" (Draft), 2009 March (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - David E. Olson, et. al., "Tables Summarizing the Sentencing of First Degree Murderers in Illinois, State Fiscal Years 1989 through 2009", 2009 September (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - David E. Olson, et. al., "Tables Summarizing the Sentencing of First Degree Murderers in Illinois, Determinate, Natural Life and Death Sentences Imposed State Fiscal Years 1989 through 2009" (FN 92), 2009 September (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Public Hearing Memo, 2009 March 2 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Public Hearing Notes, Sarah Pfouder [?], 2009 January 26 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Stenographic Report of Public Hearing, 2009 January 26 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee - Sixth and Final Report (TPS Draft), 2010 August 13 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee - Sixth and Final Report (TPS Draft), 2010 September 10 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee - Sixth and Final Report (TPS Draft), 2010 September 10 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee Sixth and Final Report (TPS Draft), 2010 October 13 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee Sixth and Final Report (included sealed CD), 2010 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Illinois Capital Punishment Reform Study Committee Sixth and Final Report, [digital files on sealed CD], 2010 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Kevin Lyons presentation material from March 2, 2010 public hearing (Box 1, Folder 31)
- State Death Penalty Law Summaries, 1994-1996, Undated; 4; 0.4
  Alphabetical by state
  Copies of many states' capital punishment legislation with summaries written by Northwestern University Law Librarian Marcia Lehr.
  - Notes describing series, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alabama - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arizona - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arkansas - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - California - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Colorado - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Delaware - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Florida - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Georgia - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Idaho - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Illinois - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Indiana - Summary of death penalty law with notes, Undated; 2011 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Kansas - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Kentucky - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Louisiana - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Maryland - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Mississippi - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Missouri - Summary of death penalty law with notes, Undated; 2011 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Nebraska, New Hampshire, Nevada - Summary of death penalty law with notes, Undated; 2011 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - New Hampshire - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - New Mexico - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - New Mexico, North Carolina, Ohio - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - New York - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Oklahoma, Oregon, South Carolina, South Dakota, Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Oregon - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Tennessee - Summary of death penalty law with notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Tennessee, Utah, Virginia, Washington, Wyoming - Summary of death penalty law with notes, Undated; 2011 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Reference Materials, 1872, 1935, 1951-2011, Undated; 5; 8.2
  This series consists of the general research and reference file of Leigh Bienen. This includes publications, reports, and legislation on subjects such as capital punishment, criminal law, rape, and prison reform.
  - William Blackstone, "Commentaries on the Laws of England in Four Books" (photocopy), 1872 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Albert E. Arent and John W. Macdonald, "The Felony Murder Doctrine and it's Application under New York Statutes", 1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Erwin L. Feiertag, "Capital Punishment in New Jersey: 1664-1950, a study of change", 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - T. C. N. Gibbens, "Sane and Insane Homicide", 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - N. M. Ollennu, "The Influence of English Law on West Africa", 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hugo A. Bedau, "Death Sentences in New Jersey", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Capital Punishment: Developments 1961 to 1965, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Emanuel Tanay, "Psychiatric Study of Homicide", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Philip M. Hauser, "The Census of 1970", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Royal Commission on Capital Punishment 1949-1953 Report, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ralph Slovenko, Tragicomedy in Court Opinions, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Charles W. Wolfram, "The Constitutional History of the Seventh Amendment", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Jurek v. Texas, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Woodson v. North Carolina, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Deborah Denno articles and letter, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Austin Sarat and Neil Vidmar, "Public Opinion, The Death Penalty, and the Eighth Amendment: Testing the Marshall Hypothesis", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Articles by R. Emerson Dobash and Russell P. Dobash, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Victoria Lynn Swigert and Ronald A. Farrell, "Normal Homicides and the Law", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Elliot S. Valenstein, Report on Psycho surgery, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Rupert V. Barry, "Furman to Gregg: The Judicial and Legislative History", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Jennifer James, "The Prostitute as Victim", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "A Ten Year Follow - up of Sex Offender Recidivism, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Amnesty International - "Proposal for a Presidential Commission on the Death Penalty in the United States of America", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Walter Berns, "Defending the Death Penalty", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Arthur L. Stinchcombe, et. al., Crime and Punishment - Changing Attitudes in America, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - David C. Baldus, et. al., "The Differential Treatment of White and Black Victim Homicide Cases In Georgia's Capital Charging and Sentencing Process: Preliminary Findings, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Capital Losses: The Price of the Death Penalty for the New York State ", 1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - F. Patrick Hubbard, Brenton G. Burry and Robert Widener, "A 'Meaningful' Basis for the Death Penalty: The Practice, Constitutionality, and Justice of Capital Punishment in South Carolina", 1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - National Center for State Courts Research Model for Determining Death Penalty Costs, ca.1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Overcrowded Time: Why Prisons are so Crowded and what can be Done", 1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Centers for Disease Control Homicide Surveillance Reports, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Janine Jason et. Al., "Homicide as a Cause of Pediatric Mortality in the United States", 1983 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Irwin I. Kimmelman, "The Death Penalty in New Jersey," New Jersey Lawyer, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Tichnell v. Maryland, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - James E. Lobsenz, "Unbridled Prosecutorial Discretion and Standardless Death Penalty Policies: The Unconstitutionality of the Washington Capital Punishment Statutory Scheme", 1984 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Beverly Martinez - Schnell and Richard J. Waxweiler, "Increases in Premature Mortality Due to Homicide - United States, 1968-1985", 1989 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - McCleskey v. Kemp, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Patrick W. O'Carroll and James A. Mercy "Regional Variation in Homicide Rates: Why is the west so Violent?", 1989 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Prejean v. Blackburn, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Research on Death Penalty costs, ca. 1989; 1988; Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Richard Van Duizend, "Comparative Proportionality Review in Death Sentence Cases", 1984 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Ralph Weisheit, "Female Homicide Offenders: Trends over time in an Institutionalized Population", 1984 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - James R. Acker, "Mandatory Capital Punishment for the Life Term Inmate who Commits Murder: Judgment of Fact and Value in Law and Social Science", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Ursula Bentele, "The Death Penalty in Georgia: Still Arbitrary", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Clippings, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Margot Garey, "The Cost of Taking a Life: Dollars and Sense of the Death Penalty", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Darnell F. Hawkins and Kenneth A. Hardy, "Black - White Imprisonment Rates: A State - by - State Analysis", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Nature of crime makes exception to Death Row rule, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Michael L. Radelet, "Rejecting the Jury: The Imposition of the Death Penalty in Florida", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Mark L. Rosenberg and James A. Mercy, "Homicide: Epidemiologic Analysis at the National Level", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Gregory Stein, "Distinguishing Among Murders When Assessing the Proportionality of the Death Penalty", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Amnesty International - USA Death Penalty Briefing, ca. 1986 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Articles by Ann Goetting on Homicide among females and wives, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Dennis Balske and James G. O'Haver, "Death Penalty Training Manual", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - John S. Carroll, et. al., "Free Press and Fair Trial: The Role of Behavioral Research", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Centers for Disease control Homicide Surveillance Report, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - McCleskey v. Kemp - Syllabus, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - James A. Mercy et. al., "Patterns of Homicide Victimization in the City of Los Angeles, 1970-79", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Patrick W. O'Carroll and James A. Mercy "Homicide Among Black Americans", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Nancy Pennington and Reid Hastie, "Evidence Evaluation in Complex Decision Making", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - State v. Palmer, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Peter Meijes Tiersma, "Dictionaries and Death: Do Capital Jurors understand Mitigation?", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - University of New Hampshire Family Research Laboratory, ca. 1986 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Ralph A. Weisheit, "When Mothers Kill Their Children", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Amnesty International - United States of America, The Death Penalty, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Articles by Peter David Blanck, 1987; 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Susan Bandes, "Southern California Law Review - Taking some Rights too seriously: The State's Right to a Fair Trial", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hugo Adam Bedau and Michael L. Radlet, "Miscarriages of Justice in Potentially Capital Cases", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Lisa Gayle Bradley, "Proportionality in Capital and Non-Capital Sentencing: An Eighth Amendment Enigma", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Caseload and Cost Projections for Habeas Corpus Death Penalty Cases in fiscal years 1998 and 1989, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Centers for Disease Control - Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Pat Doherty and Kevin McNally, "Confronting the Question of the Victim's Family: Before, During and After Trial", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Thomas Havlena, "Abolishing the Death Penalty - Why? How? When?", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Report to the Deputy Attorney General on Capital Punishment and the Sentencing Commission, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Lawrence T. White, "Juror Decision Making in the Capital Penalty Trial", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Brian Wiersema and Karen Kindley, "An Attribute Approach to Homicide Classification", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - William Wilbanks, "Reactions to McCleskey vs. Georgia", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Margo Wilson and Martin Daly, Articles on Spousal Homicide, gendered culture, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Leslie Abramson and Andrea Lyon, "Control of the Courtroom at Trial", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bureau of Justice Statistics - Murder in Large Urban Counties, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Jacqueline Cook, "Coming Full Circle: A Return to Arbitrary Sentencing Patterns in Capital Punishment Cases", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Mary Elizabeth Holland, "McClesky v. Kemp: Racism and the Death Penalty", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Kansas Coalition Against the Death Penalty, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Longitudinal Court Outcome Study of Individuals Accused of Homicide Reported in 1988, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - McDowell Juror Questionnaire, ca. 1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Michael L. Radelet and Margaret Vandiver, Capital Punishment in America: An Annotated Biography, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Michael L. Radelet and Margaret Vandiver, Capital Punishment in America: An Annotated Biography, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Gennaro F. Vito and Thomas J. Keil, "Capital Sentencing in Kentucky: An Analysis of the Factors Influencing Decision Making in the post - Gregg period" (pre-publication), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Gennaro F. Vito and Deborah G. Wilson "Back From the Dead: Tracking the Progress of Kentucky's Furman - Commuted Death Row Population", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - James R. Acker and Elizabeth R. Walsh, "Challenging the Death Penalty Under State Constitutions", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - James R. Acker, "The Grand Jury and Capital Punishment: Rethinking the Role of an Ancient Institution Under the Modern Jurisprudence of Death", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - James R. Acker, "Thirty Years of Social Science in Supreme Court Criminal Cases", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Jonathan D. Casper, Kennette Benedict, and Jo L. Perry, "Juror Decision Making, Attitudes, and the Hindsight Bias", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Clippings, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Federal Death Penalty Act of 1989, Racial Justice Act of 1994 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Herb Haines, "Primum Non Nocere: Chemical Execution and the Limits of Medical social Control", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Jury Comprehension in Complex Cases, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Stephen P. Klein, Allan F. Abrahamse, and John E. Rolph, "Relationship of Offender and Victim Race to Death Penalty Sentences in California", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Memorandum in Opposition to S.600/A.1070, New York Lawyers Against the Death Penalty, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - New Jersey Supreme Court Task Force on Minority Concerns - Interim report, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Greg Newbold, "Capital Punishment in New Zealand: An Experiment that Failed", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Non-Statutory Mitigating Circumstances, 1989 January 4 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Daniel Okada and Arnold Raimondo, "The Incarcerated Vietnam Vet: Preliminary Investigations on the Vietnam Veteran and the Criminal Justice System, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Ben F. Overton, "Trial Judges and Political Elections: A Time for Re-Examination", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Raymond Paternoster and AnnMarie Kazyaka, "An Examination of Comparatively Excessive Death Sentences in South Carolina 1979-1987", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - D. Michael Risinger, et. al., "Exorcism of Ignorance as a Proxy for Rational Knowledge: The Lessons of Handwriting Identification 'Expertise' ", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Sawyer v. Smith - Brief of Amicus Curiae, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Shari Seidman Diamond, Jonathan D. Casper and Lynne Ostergren, "Blindfolding the Jury", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Silagy v. Peters III, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Statement of Ronald J. Tabak on behalf of the American Bar Association before the Committee on the Judiciary of the United States Senate on Racial Discrimination and the Death Penalty, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Testimony of Julius L. Chambers concerning the Racial Justice Ace of 1988, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Neil J. Vidmar, "Empirical Research and the Issues of Jury Competence, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Neil J. Vidmar and Regina A. Schuller, "Juries and Expert Evidence: Social Framework Testimony", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Hans Zeisel and Alec M. Gallup, "Death Penalty Sentiment in the United States", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - American Bar Association support for H.R. 4737 Habeas Corpus Revision Act of 1990 and "Fatal Defense " The National Law Journal (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - American Journal of Public Health, "The Prevalence of Severe Mental Disorder among male urban Jail Detainees", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Capital Report - Death Penalty Litigation Section, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Census of State and Federal Correctional Facilities, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Clippings, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Correctional Populations in the United States, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - William J. Curran, "The Ethics of Medical Participation in Capital Punishment by Intravenous Drug Injection", 1980 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - "Death Penalty Sentencing: Research Indicates Pattern of Racial Disparities", Report to Senate and House committees on the Judiciary, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - General Accounting Office Report to Senate and House Committees on the Judiciary - "Death Penalty Sentencing: Research Indicates Pattern of Racial Disparities", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Governor's Management Review Commission, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Lawrence A. Greenfeld, "Capital Punishment 1990", Bureau of Justice Statistics Bulletin, ca. 1990 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - David A. Kaplan and Lauren Picker "The Executioner's Handyman", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - James Luginbuhl, "Successfully Challenging the Highly Pro - Death Juror", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Walter F. Murphy and Joseph Tanenhaus, "Publicity, Public Opinion, and the Court", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Laura B. Myers, "Prosecutorial and Judicial Decision - Making: A Contextual Comparison of Charging and Sentencing Decisions", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Silagy v. Warden, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Tom W. Smith, "Liberal and Conservative Trends in the United States Since World War II", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Statement of Randall M. Dana, National Association of Criminal Defense Lawyers before the Subcommittee on Crime, U.S. House Judiciary Committee, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 69)